准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
咬一口
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
给你  先生
Here you go, sir
加全套配料的巨无霸至尊蟹黄堡
A King Size Ultra Krabby Supreme with the works
双层面糊炸制
double batter-fried
串在棍上
on a stick
谢谢了
Thanks
傻子一个
Barnacle head
你说什么
Pardon me?
你忘了拿蛋黄酱
You forgot your mayonnaise
谢谢了
Thanks
看看他们吃那些垃圾
Look at them eating that garbage
简直恶心
It's disgusting
让我都要吐了
They're sickening
我恨蟹黄堡
I hate Krabby Patties
真好笑  章鱼哥
Good one, Squidward
好什么
Good what?
搞的好像你不知道似的
Like you don't know
你刚说
Saying
我恨蟹黄堡
"I hate Krabby Patties"
真的太搞笑了
That's hilarious
大家都爱蟹黄堡的
Everyone loves Krabby Patties
对  我不算大家
Yeah, well, not me
真会讲笑话
You're good at that
大家听我说
Hey, everyone
章鱼哥说他不喜欢蟹黄堡
Squid says he doesn't like Krabby Patties
太好笑了  章鱼哥
That's really good, Squidward
笑死我了
That's really funny
不准怂恿他们
Don't encourage them
他们这样不会走
They'll never leave
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squidward
真的很好笑
It's just so funny
要知道我们都说
You know what we say
唯一不喜欢蟹黄堡的那位
The only people who don't like a Krabby Patty
从来就没尝过蟹黄堡
have never tasted one
是我没错了
That's me
从来没吃过
Never had one
永远也不会吃
never will
什么
What?
你刚说什么了
What did you say?
我从来没吃过蟹黄堡  永远也不会吃
I've never had a Krabby Patty, and never will
真对不起
I'm sorry
我觉得不
I don't
我从来没吃过蟹黄堡
I've never had a Krabby Patty
这些字
Those words
怎么可能会组成那样一句话呢
Is it possible to use them
in a sentence together like that?
我从来没吃过蟹黄堡
I've never had a Krabby Patty
从来没吃过蟹黄堡
Never had a Krabby Patty?
那你现在就得吃一个
Well, you've gotta have one right now
难怪你一直都很悲惨
No wonder you're always so miserable
给  尝一口
Here, try this
把那个垃圾给我拿开
Get that garbage outta my face
尝一下就会爱上的
If you try it, you'll love it
尝一口所谓食物的高辐射混球吗
Try one of those radioactive
sludge balls you call food?
然后你是不是要我跟派大星跳方块舞
Next I suppose you'll want me to go
square-dancing with Patrick
抱歉  派大星
Sorry, Patrick
吃嘛  你一定会
Come on, you're gonna
不吃
No
隧道快打通  火车要进去了
Open up the tunnel, here comes the train
不吃
No
你耳朵里面有什么
What's that in your ear?
别闹了
Quit it
快点  嘴巴张大
Come on, open wide
海绵宝宝  就算我被困到了井底
SpongeBob, if I were trapped at the bottom of a well
困个三年
for three years
只有这个蟹黄堡能吃
with nothing to eat but that Krabby Patty
老子也要先吃我的腿
I'd eat my own legs first
就算多长几条腿也不吃
And not just the extra ones
可这个对你有益
But it's good for you
这叫有益
Good for you?
那汉堡就是个热量炸弹
That thing is a heart attack on a bun
不是那意思  章鱼哥
No, Squidward
我意思是
I meant
对你的灵魂有益
good for your soul
得了吧你
Puh-leez
我根本没灵魂
I have no soul
那好吧  就吃一半
Okay, just half
不吃
No
四分之一
A quarter?
不吃
No
一口
One bite?
不吃
No
闻一闻就行
Just smell it
我在外面都不想要这玩意
If I didn't want it out there
怎么会在这厕所里对这玩意感兴趣
what makes you think I'd find it more appealing in here?
拜托嘛  章鱼哥
Come on, Squidward
不吃
No
吃一口
One bite
不吃
No
你绝对不会后悔的
You won't be sorry
不吃
No
特好吃的
It's delicious
听好了  海绵宝宝
Listen, SpongeBob
你打算要这样下去多久
how long are you prepared to keep this up?
给我
Give me that
等我死了
When I die
别来玷污我的葬礼
you stay away from my funeral
难道我真的
Do I really
啊
Why
这个蟹黄堡可能就是最
this Krabby Patty may be the most
垃圾
Horrible
恶心
Putrid
做工粗劣
Poorly prepared
下贱
Vile
倒胃口
Unappetizing
蹩脚的烂三明治
Disgusting excuse for a sandwich
让这玩意下肚是我此生最大的不悦
it has ever been my displeasure
to have slither down my throat
可是
But
我诅咒这个蟹黄堡
And I curse this Krabby Patty
还有所有喜欢蟹黄堡的家伙
and all who enjoy them
趁早踏进他们应得的坟里去
to an early and well-deserved grave
懂我意思
Get it?
可是根本没道理啊
But it doesn't make any sense
蟹黄堡绝对质量上乘
The Krabby Patty is an absolute good
大家都无法抗拒它美味的魅力
Nobody is immune to its tasty charms
我不算大家
Nobody but me
你确定吗
Are you sure?
这样看起来还不确定吗
Does this look unsure to you?
确定了
No
很好
Good
现在快去传话
Now go spread the word
快点
Come on
还活着
Still alive
太好吃了
So delicious
浪费了这么多年
All the wasted years
我得再吃点
I got to have more
可是等下
But wait
刚给他演那出  他肯定不会放过我
After that performance, he'd never let me live it down
我得溜进去偷
I gotta sneak one
就偷一个
just one
然后我就彻底戒掉那玩意
then I'm off the stuff for good
应该不可能啊
I didn't think it was possible
可能是真的有人不喜欢蟹黄堡吧
but I guess some people just don't like Krabby Patties
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
什么事  章鱼哥
Yes, Squidward?
来三层蟹黄堡巨无霸  上加海草面包
I need a Triple Krabby Supreme on a kelp bun
再多加海腌椰菜然后
with extra sea pickle and
然后烤焦  行不行
and burn it to a crisp, okay?
马上就来
Coming right up
我跟你说  章鱼哥
Listen, Squidward
我要为之前的所作所为道歉
I want to apologize for before
我只是想让你高兴
I was only trying to make you happy
但现在我明白了
But now I've learned
各类人都需要得到包容
there's room for all kinds of people
不必强求他们都喜欢一样的东西
and they don't all have to like the same things
不要消失啊
Don't go
虽然我强烈反对你的决定
While I strongly disagree with your decision
但我还是要接受
I accept it
要知道  我可不常做这样的蟹黄堡
You know, it's not often I get to make one like this
我要看人家咬第一口时的表情
I want to see the look on their face
when they take that first bite
三层蟹黄堡巨无霸
Triple Krabby Supreme
有谁点了三层蟹黄堡巨无霸吗
Did somebody order a Triple Krabby Supreme?
肯定是走了
They must have left
那个  要不你就
Well, uh, why don't you just uh
把它放在这  人家可能会回来
leave it out here in case they come back
不行
Nope
这样特别的蟹黄堡得趁新鲜吃  而且
a patty this special should be eaten fresh and
我有二十多分钟没吃这宝贝了
well, I haven't had one of these babies
in over 20 minutes
所以说
so
不论点餐的是谁
Well, whoever they were
品味都不错
they had great taste
那位都不知道错过什么了
They don't know what they're missing
回去工作吧
Well, back to work
我得怎么办
What do I have to do?
难道要从垃圾堆里翻一个来吃吗
Eat one out of the garbage?
真希望我能吃下这个
I wish I could eat this
可我都要撑死了
but I'm so darn full
那好吧
Oh well
真就垃圾了
I had to say garbage
天赐良机啊
but okay
不会吧  怎么会这样
Oh no, what's this doing here?
这个蟹黄堡应该要被火化掉的
This patty should be cremated
虽然我知道你不喜欢它
I know you didn't like him
但你能来参加葬礼  意义十分重大
but it means so much that you came
老婆
Honey?
我必须要把蟹黄堡弄到手
I have got to get my hands on a Krabby Patty
谁都拦不住我
And no one's going to stop me
就在那
There it is
蟹黄堡保险库
真是见鬼了
Holy shrimp
都不知道要从哪开始吃了
I don't know where to start
重点就是只有你
All that matters is that it's just you
还有我
and me
周围空无一人
and nobody
章鱼哥
Squidward?
是你吗
Is that you?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
我都是凌晨三点钟来上班的
I always come to work at 3:00 am
我在这个点来数芝麻
This is when I count the sesame seeds
你又来这干什么
What are you doing here?
我忘拿我的
I forgot my
蟹黄堡保险库干嘛开着
And why is the patty vault open?
我觉得
I thought that
你干嘛把一个蟹黄堡藏在背后了
And why are you holding a patty behind your back?
我我我
I-I-I-
我没有藏
No, I didn't do
你干嘛这么紧张
And why are you acting so nervous?
你干嘛出这么多汗
And why are you sweating so much?
你干嘛看着这么饿
And why do you look so hungry?
你
And
不对  你听我说
No, no, wait
不是你想的那样
it's not what you think
这  这可是个天大的误会
Th-this is a big misunderstanding
你得相信我
You've got to believe me
我
I
听好  我跟你说
Listen, I am telling you
最好给我听好了  海绵宝宝
You better listen to me, SpongeBob
你喜欢蟹黄堡  对不对章鱼哥
You like Krabby Patties, don't you, Squidward?
对
Yes
我承认了  海绵宝宝
I admit it, SpongeBob
我爱蟹黄堡
I love Krabby Patties
我就知道  章鱼哥
I knew it all along, Squidward
没有谁能抵挡得住蟹黄堡的魅力
No one can resist a Krabby Patty
章鱼哥  你吃多少了
Squidward, how many are you eating?
章鱼哥
Squidward
章鱼哥  不能一口气吃掉所有蟹黄堡
Squidward, you can't eat all those patties at one time
章鱼哥
Squidward
那会怎么样
What's gonna happen?
我会爆炸吗
Am I gonna blow up?
会更惨
No, worse
蟹黄堡会先跑你大腿里面
it'll go right to your thighs
大腿嘛
My thighs?
然后再爆炸
And then you'll blow up
是啊
Yeah
我还记得我吃的第一个蟹黄堡
I remember my first Krabby Patty
恶霸
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
滑浪学校
不好意思  小姐
Excuse me, Miss
我都不想再打你小报告了
I don't want to have to report you again
我只是想知道
I was just wondering
本子左边的作业铅笔
Is it the "homework pencil" on the left side of the paper
要挨着考试铅笔好
next to the "quiz pencil"
还是要自个到右边去好
or over on the right side, all by itself
还是
or
那铅笔怕是得要插到你的
I think it goes stuck inside your
等下  有了
Wait, I got it
考试铅笔要放这里  紧挨着作文铅笔
The "quiz pencil" goes right over here
next to the "essay" pencil
作文铅笔要侧着放  指到本子上面
And the "essay" pencil gets turned sideways
towards the notepad
以备写作文用
Just in case I have to write an essay
同学们好
Good morning, class
抱歉迟到了
Sorry I'm late
我来的路上碰到堵车了
I got caught in traffic on the way here
还以为我都要堵车堵一辈子  真要命
when that whole
"I'm gonna be doing this for the rest of my life" thing
reared its ugly head
还有
and I
还
I
总之呢  我们今天来了一位新同学
Anyway, we have a new student starting today
就一起用满脸笑容迎接比目鱼平平吧
So let's all put on a happy face for Flats the Flounder
跟班上的同学们做自我介绍吧  平平
Tell the class something about yourself, Flats
那个
Well
我喜欢揍别人
I like to kick people's butts
好幽默
What a card
平平  来挑下你的座位
Now, Flats, it's time to pick your seat
爱坐哪里就坐哪里
Just go ahead and sit anywhere you like
好了  同学们
Okay, class
记得上个星期
as you remember last week
嗨  我叫海绵宝宝
Hi, I'm SpongeBob
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
我要揍你一顿
I'm gonna kick your butt
第二次讲这笑话更幽默了
That joke was almost funnier the second time
不对
No
我认真的
I mean it
这回的笑话怕是说
That time it almost seemed like
我认真的
你真是认真的
you did mean it
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff
什么事  海绵宝宝
Yes, SpongeBob?
我能失陪一辈子吗
Can I be excused for the rest of my life?
不能  海绵宝宝
Why no, SpongeBob
我在讲一节枯燥到得靠咖啡提神的课
I'm in the middle of a coffee-fueled sermon right now
这课的内容可不能漏听了
You can't afford to miss this information
好的  泡芙老师
Yes, Mrs. Puff
对不起  泡芙老师
Sorry, Mrs. Puff
现在有谁自愿上台吗
Now, can I please have a volunteer
to come up to the board?
你来上吧  平平
How about you, Flats?
请你给我们画出
Please draw for us
基本十字路口的示意图  平平
a diagram of a basic four-way intersection, Flats
快转身给全班看你画的示意图  同学
Please turn and show the class what you drew, honey
天哪  好有创意
My, how very creative
我们班出了个画家
We have an artist in the class
我真搞不懂
I just don't understand
为什么平平要揍我
Why would Flats want to kick my butt?
我都没跟人家说够两个字
I haven't said two words to the guy
嗨  我叫海绵宝宝
Hi, I'm SpongeBob
一
One
二
two
不好  讲了七个字
Oh no, that's three
三 个
我要怎么办
What am I gonna do?
什么声音
What's that?
有人来了
Someone's coming
离得越来越近了
They're getting closer
我必须要自然点
I just got to act natural
真不错
Oh, that's real nice
我本来还以为来的会是
I thought for sure that was gonna be
平平
Flats?
先生好
Hello, sir
最近揍人揍得舒服吗
Kicked any good butts lately?
我还记得上个星期
Yeah, I remember last week
我把那个人揍得落花流水
I was kickin' this guy's butt real good
那个人弯下身子说
And he leans over and says
要知道生活就像是一大水桶的木屑
"Hey, ya know, life's like a bucket of wood shavings
不过如果木屑是在提桶里的话
"except for when the shavings are in a pail
那样生活就像是一大提桶的木屑了
then it's like a pail of wood shavings"
这个故事对我好有启发
That story really speaks to me
真的吗
Really?
启发什么了
What's it say?
启发了我  要加倍用力来揍你
It says now I'm gonna kick your butt twice as hard
把小蜗的饮水盆交给小蜗保管
And I'll leave Gary's water bowl to Gary
把我窗帘交给
and my curtains to
海神王啊  我做不到
Oh, Neptune, I just can't do this
死刑犯牢房  请下一位接听电话
Death row, "next-in-line" speaking
喂  我要订一份外卖
Hi, I'd like to place an order for delivery
派大星
Patrick
是你吗
Is that you?
是我啊  马里奥
Yeah, hey, Mario
我要来份大份的加双倍橄榄  双倍
Let me get a large, double olive, double
派大星  你听好了
Patrick, listen
是我  海绵宝宝
It's me, SpongeBob
我要你来帮忙
I need your help
你现在是在匹萨城里上班吗
You're working at Pizza Castle now?
说什么
What?
不是的  你听好
No, listen
我有危险了
I'm in big trouble
驾校新来了个同学  想要揍我
There's a new guy at school here
and he wants kick my butt
我跟你说  你又大又壮
Listen, you're big and strong
你可不可以来这一趟
Do you think you can come down here
帮忙来揍他
maybe rough him up a bit
好让他放过我吗
just to get him off my back?
求你了  派大星
Please, Patrick
我好怕
I'm so scared
我感觉我都要吐了
it feels like I'm gonna throw up
那边店里没关门
No, they're not closed
我知道你想要加橄榄
I know, you want olives
派大星  你有在听吗
Patrick, you there?
真对不起  海绵宝宝
I'm sorry, SpongeBob
我刚在跟我社区学院的校友平平聊天
I was just talking to
my old community college buddy, Flats
我在汽水店里碰见他的  你说怪不怪
I bumped into him at the soda store, isn't that funny?
我们肯定有好几年没有碰过面了
It must have been years since we've seen each other
该挂了
Well, let me get going
他得马上回驾校
He's got to go back to school soon
说是他必须得去揍某个人
He says he's got to kick somebody's butt
喂
Hello?
是匹萨城吗
Is this Pizza Castle?
进来  海绵宝宝
Come in, SpongeBob
泡芙老师  我可不可以改上别的班
Mrs. Puff, can I be in a different class?
为什么
But why?
我说不来
I can't tell you
怎么就说不来
Why ever not?
我就是说不来  泡芙老师
I just can't, Mrs. Puff
我就只能说  我正面临生命危险
My physical being is at stake, let's just leave it at that
海绵宝宝  你可以向我倾诉的
SpongeBob, you can tell me anything
要相信这一点
You've got to believe that
那
Well
好吧
okay
但是必须要发誓不跟别人讲
But only if you promise to keep it between us
好的
Of course
平平说他要揍我
Flats says he's gonna kick my butt
什么
What?
我的课上不准许出现揍人现象
There shall be no butt-kicking in any class of mine
大家都老大不小了
This is an adult program
海绵宝宝  就交给我好了
SpongeBob, just leave it to me
谢谢你  泡芙老师
Thanks, Mrs. Puff
就知道可以信任你
I knew I could count on you
饭吃得香不香  海绵宝宝
Have a nice lunch, SpongeBob?
当然香  泡芙老师
Yes, Mrs. Puff
海绵宝宝  我帮你跟平平讲了
SpongeBob, I talked to Flats for you
还特别提了你名字
I used your name
都是场误会
It was all a misunderstanding
什么
You what?
他根本就不是要揍你
He was never going to kick your butt at all
知道吗  海绵宝宝
You see, SpongeBob
平平是从一个只要揍别人
Flats is from a town where "kicking someone's butt"
就表示想要交朋友的镇上来的
means that he wants to be your friend
那边揍别人也可能表示周末一起锻炼
and maybe play some sports with you on weekends
我拉肚子了
I got diarrhea
你是平平他爸吗
Are you Flats's Dad?
对  我就是
Why, yes, I am
那就好
Okay
跟你说  我不知道要怎么办才好
See, I didn't know where else to turn
派大星帮不了我
Patrick couldn't help me
泡芙老师反而让事情更严重了
and Mrs. Puff only made it worse
我上学就坐在你儿子平平旁边
I sit next to your son Flats in school
他只不过是个好孩子
and he is a fine boy and all
我其实也不太想要让你误会了
and I don't want you to take this the wrong way
可是他真的想要揍我
but he wants to kick my butt
爸  你在干什么
Dad, what are you doing?
啥也没干  儿子
Nothing, son
我怎么跟你说的  不准跟陌生人讲话
What did I tell you about talking to strangers?
现在他要揍我了
Now he's going to kick my butt
都借过
Out of my way
那人要揍我  看到了吗
Can't you see he's going to kick my butt?
你们好  年轻人
Hi there, young people
公交站
今天真是好天气
Nice day today
所以说你喜欢揍人  是不是
So you like kickin' butts, do ya?
那咱就好好来揍你  臭老头
Well, we'll show you, old man
好  好
Okay, okay
我得离开这个镇子
I got to skip town
开始新生活
Start a new life
用化名来混日子
Live under an assumed name
宝宝绵海
BobPants SpongeSquare
好名字
Yeah, that's good
长出胡子  然后再剃掉
Grow a beard and then shave it off
从此过上幸福快乐的日子
and live happily ever after
是啊  不过你忘了还有我要揍你这段
Yeah, except you forgot the part where I kick your butt
裤头村垃圾
平平  你好点了没
Hey, Flats, you feeling better?
什么
What?
我这是在哪
Where am I?
你现在是在住院
Why, you're in the hospital
这位年轻人救了你一命
This young boy saved your life
他连续给你做了五小时的心肺复苏
He performed CPR for five hours straight
是啊
Yeah
医生开始几分钟就说你没事了
they said you'd be okay after the first few minutes
不过我只想确保万无一失
but I just wanted to be sure
我好感动
I'm touched
等我揍你那会  我一定会记好的
I'll have to remember that when I'm kicking your butt
这些花是送我的吗
Those flowers for me?
他还是要揍我
He's still gonna kick my butt
到底还得教训你多少次  臭老头
How many times
do we have to teach you this lesson, old man?
我好爱年轻人
I love the young people
公交站
小蜗  我还年轻不能被揍
Gary, I'm too young to have my butt kicked
我这一生还有好多的事情没有做
There are so many things in life
that I haven't gotten to do
请稍等  将为您的通话进行转接
Hang on, I'll transfer your call
谁啊
Who is it?
平平
Flats
揍人时间到
It's butt-kicking time
小蜗  我要让你知道点事
Gary, there's something I want you to know
可我太害怕  记不起来了
But I'm too scared to remember what it is
开揍了
Let's do it
小蜗快走
Go away, Gary
我不想要你看到这一幕
I don't want you to see this
会很难看的
it'll be ugly
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
等下
Hold on
行了  我准备好了
Okay, I'm ready
都说我准备好了
I said, I'm ready
没听到吗
Didn't you hear me?
都说我准备好了
I said I'm ready
好痒
That tickled
小蜗
Gary
我在吸收他揍我的力  好像我是某种
I'm absorbing his blows like I was made of some kind of
疏松材料组成的
spongy material
知道什么意思了吧
And do you know what that means?
我明天可以去上班了
I get to go to work tomorrow
你有七吗
Do you have any sevens?
平平  你没事吧
Flats, are you okay?
不要给我欢呼了  我的大人同学们
Do not cheer me, my fellow adult classmates
平平才是真正的受害者
Flats was the real victim here
被社会所迫走上暴力不归路的受害者
A victim of a society that's riding down
a violent road to nowhere
我管这条不归路叫
a road I call
暴路
"Violence Road"
抱歉同学们  我迟到了
Sorry I'm late, class
我
I
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你居然把新同学给打趴下了
I can't believe you beat up a new student
我现在要揍你了
I'm going to kick your butt